Daniyal Abbas

Diversified experience of over **02 years** in different companies. Got the opportunities to gain **practical exposure while studying in University**; as done with my degree so feel much more prepared for practical / professional career.

I am seeking an enhanced role in **IT Networks Management** where my energy, knowledge and passion for IT field can be fulfilled.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Mob: +92-336-4779557 **Tel:** +92-42-37106905

Email: Daniyalabbasi1993@gmail.com





Key IT Skills:

MS Office, System Administration, C++, Network Security, SQL Server 2008, SQL Server 2012, Crystal Reports, MySQL, Workbench, Cisco call manager, PFSense, windows server 2012 R2, 2016, 2019, Windows 7, 8,10. DC, ADC, File server, Print server, DHCP, DNS Trisoft Technology Pvt Ltd Network Engineer (Jan 2020 - Till Date)

My main responsibilities include:

- Administration of the networks and servers to ensure maximum performance in terms of availability, accessibility, speed and security.
- Installation, configuration and troubleshooting of domains, servers and network systems.
- Management of all kinds of server installation, migration, backup and restoration.
- Troubleshooting arising problems, user management using Active directory.
- Manage and provide effective ongoing support to customers on integration projects and implementation.
- Manage Hardware / software inventory.
- Configuration and management of Email Servers (Hostgator, Godaddy & O365).
- Implementation of data backup using Veeam and goodync & freefilesync.
- Emails backup using Cobian.
- Purchasing IT inventory as per requirement
- Dealing with vendors for procurement of IT products.
- Configure USB restriction on specific computers using group policy.
- Developed secure data storage solution of local employees.
- Configure PF Sense as gateway with redundant WAN links.
- Configure Windows failover cluster, SQL failover cluster, NLB cluster.
- Installing and managing Hyper-V server for VM, also have work on VMware.
- Installing and configure Active Directory and Group policy.
- Database Management in SQL Server, MySQL;
- Installation network and shared printers and support.
- Performing primary and disaster recovery operations, protecting data, from attacks, and replacing faulty network hardware components when necessary.
- Maintain security and database, backup, and redundancy strategies;

Intelligence Metering Systems (IMS) Network Engineer

(April 2018 - Till Date)

Intelligent Metering Systems (Put) Ltd. is **rapidly growing high-tech corporation**; focusing on research, development, manufacturing and services in the field of **advanced smart energy meters and metering systems** including single phase, three phase, automatic energy management systems (AMR and AMI) in technical collaboration with **Holley Metering China**.

As Network Engineer I got the opportunity to deploy IMS system in Karachi Electric (KE); the most advanced and technical smart metering solution in the industry.

My main responsibilities include:

- Server Installation and other support.
- Provide IT support to local and remote employees of the company.
- Working on Apache for web application deployment.
- Configure USB restriction on specific computers using group policy.
- Developed secure data storage solution of local employees.
- Configure PF Sense as gateway with redundant WAN links.
- Administration of GoDaddy server.
- Configure Windows failover cluster, SQL failover cluster, NLB cluster.

TECHNICAL Skills

Microsoft Office

• • • • • • • • •

SQL Server 2018

• • • • • • • • •

Crystal Reports

• • • • • • • • •

MySQL Workbench

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$

LANGUAGES (WRITTEN & SPOKEN)

Urdu (Native)



English



- Installing and managing Hyper-V server for VM, also have work on VMware.
- Installing and configure Active Directory and Group policy.
- (ECEP) Web Application support.
- Database Management in SQL Server, MySQL;
- Maintaining computer networks, hardware, software, and other related systems;
- Performing primary and disaster recovery operations, protecting data, from attacks, and replacing faulty network hardware components when necessary.
- Maintaining, monitoring and support to primary site system which is deployed in KE Karachi.
- Maintain security and database, backup, and redundancy strategies;
- Maintaining IT inventory;

The Smart School (TSS)

(Apr 2016 - Sep 2016)

IT - Intern

TSS is a franchise model of The City School. The group established in Karachi in 1978, now one of the largest private school networks in Pakistan. It currently has 195 schools in 54 cities with over 60,000 students and 9000 employees. International presence is in 8 different countries. Group companies are Shalimar Construction Company (SCC), The Smart School (TSS) and Ideal Creations.

Worked as an intern in multiple functions like:

- Provide network support and troubleshoot to resolve issues;
- Software Developments initial level (.Net, C#, SQL Server 2008 R2, Crystal Reports, MVC);
- Managed Smart School Web Portal and conducted training session of school staff on this web portal;
- · Maintaining IT inventory

Capital TV Jr. IT Engineer

(Apr 2015 – Dec 2015)

Capital TV is an Urdu language Pakistan television news channel launched on April 10, 2013 based in Islamabad, with bureaus in capital cities of Pakistan.

My responsibilities were:

- Diagnose and troubleshoot technical issues, and network configuration.
- Manage and monitor all installed systems and infrastructure.
- Installation network and shared printers and support.
- Manage and install printer on network.

Dunya TV Network IT - Intern

(Jun 2013 – Aug 2013)

Dunya News is a 24 hours Urdu language news and current affairs television channel from Pakistan. It is governed and operated by the National Communication Services Pvt. Ltd. Its head office is situated at Lahore, Pakistan.

My responsibilities were:

- Trouble shooting at operating system level.
- System configurations and installations.
- Network and shared printers management.

TRAININGS & CERTIFICATIONS

- Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer (MCSE) (Corvit Systems) 2019
- Cisco Certified Network Administrator (CCNA) (Corvit Systems) 2019 (Certified)
- Red Hat Certified System Administrator (RHCSA) (Corvit Systems) 2019
- Cisco Certified Network Professional (CCNP) (Corvit Systems) 2019
- Huawei Certified Network Administrator Security (HCNA Security) (Corvit Systems) (Certified)
- Voice (Hands on experience on cisco unified communication manager) (Corvit Systems)2019

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

Bahauddin Zakariya University Multan

2016

BS Computer Sciences

Punjab College of Information Technology Intermediate in Computer Sciences (ICS)

2012

INTERESTS & ACTIVITIES

• Current Affairs, Cricket